Preliminary guide to the Andrews Memorial Bookplate Collection of Irene D. Andrews Pace (Personal Bookplates)
Yale University Arts Library
Andrews Memorial Bookplate Collection of Irene D. Andrews Pace (Personal Bookplates)
1924-1962
1950-1960
BKP 2
Yale University Arts Library
19.18
(26 boxes)
The collection contains bookplates and other documentation related to the personal ex-libris designs of Irene Dwen Andrews Pace (1892-1962).
Andrews, Irene Dwen, 1892-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Irene D. Andrews Pace, 1963, in memory of Dr. Edmund Andrews (Yale 1913) and his father, Dr. E. Wyllys Andrews.
Conditions Governing Access
Requires curatorial permission before use.
Biographical / Historical
Born Irene Greene Dwen, Mrs. Pace (1892-1962) was an avid bookplate collector from the early 1920s until 1962. In addition to over 150,000 plates in her collection, she also maintained a reference library related to bookplates as well as heraldry and biographical research. Pace commissioned several hundred bookplates for herself. In 1936, she published Owners of Books: The Dissipations of a Collector.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains bookplates and other documentation related to the personal ex-libris designs of Irene Dwen Andrews Pace (1892-1962). Pace was a prolific bookplate collector who acquired nearly 300 personal ex-libris designs. Her personal collection includes designs commissioned directly from artists as well as several commercial designs. Pace also saved trial proofs and final prints along with any correspondence, carved wood blocks or engraved plates, original sketches, or other printed ephemera by the artists.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Bookplates – Mounted. II. Bookplates – Unmounted. III. Process Materials. IV. Correspondence and Ephemera.
Bookplates -- Specimens.; Bookplates; Sketches; Artists' proofs; Printing blocks (printing surfaces); Printing plates; Correspondence
- Bookplates – Mounted, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged sequentially according to numbers assigned by Pace, which are chronological by date of commission.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains bookplates and supporting materials related to Pace's personal ex-libris designs. These materials were mounted and stored in binders according to the same collecting practices for her other bookplate collections.
  - #1 Irene Dwen Andrews, 1924; Seymour, Ralph Fletcher, 1876-1966 (Box 1)
  - #2 Dr. Edmund Andrews, [1926]; Fairman, Margaret (Box 1)
  - #3 Dr. E. Wyllys Andrews, undated; Mitchell (Box 1)
  - #4 Irene, Edmund & Wyllys Andrews, 1929; Franke, Hans, 1892- (Box 1)
  - #5 Irene and Edmund Andrews, 1929; Turner, W. McAllister (Box 1)
  - #6 Irene and Edmund Andrews, 1930-1932; Mahalov, Ann (Box 1)
  - #7 Irene Greene Dwen Andrews, 1930; Yeats, Jack B. (Jack Butler), 1871-1957 (Box 1)
  - #8 Edmund, Irene & Wyllys Andrews, 1931; Turner, W. McAllister (Box 1)
  - #9 Irene Greene Dwen Andrews, 1932; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #10 Irene Andrews, 1932; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #11 Vahine Irene & Tane Edmund Andrews, 1932; Pierce, Ted (Box 1)
  - #12 Irene D. Andrews [by C.K.], [1934] (Box 1)
  - #13 Irene & Edmund Andrews, 1934; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #14 Irene Andrews, 1934; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #15 Irene D. Andrews, [1939]; Fingesten, Michel, 1884-1943 (Box 1)
  - #16 E. Wyllys Andrews IV, 1934; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #17 Irene and Edmund Andrews, 1936; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #18 Irene Dwen Andrews, [1936] (Box 1)
  - #19 Irene D. Andrews, [1937]; Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828 (Box 1)
    This bookplate is a restrike from a woodblock engraved by Bewick.
  - #20 Irene Andrews, [1937]; Casper, Melvin (Box 1)
  - #21 Andrews, [1938]; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #22 Irene and Edmund Andrews, 1938; Jameson, J. W. (Box 1)
  - #23 Irene and Edmund Andrews, [1939]; Geritz, Franz (Box 1)
    This bookplate is hand colored by Raoul Gerard.
  - #24-#28 Irene Andrews, [1940]; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 1)
  - #29 Irene Andrews, 1942; Powers, Grant (Box 1)
  - #30 Irene Dwen Andrews, 1942; Powers, Grant (Box 1)
  - #31 Irene Dwen Pace, 1946; Seymour, Ralph Fletcher, 1876-1966 (Box 1)
  - #32 Rear Admiral Ernest Milton Pace Jr., 1946; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 1)
  - #33 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1946 1954; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 1)
  - #34 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1947; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 1)
  - #35 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1947; Bissiri Brothers (Box 1)
  - #36 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1947; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 1)
  - #37 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1948; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 1)
  - #38 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1948 (Box 1)
  - #39 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1948]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 1)
  - #40 Irene D. Pace, 1948; Browne, Robert Cave (Box 1)
  - #41 Irene Dwen Pace, 1948; Vincenti, Cesare (Box 1)
    Also includes three proposed sketches.
  - #42 Irene Dwen Pace, 1943-1948; Ferenzona, Raoul (Box 1)
  - #43 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1948 (Box 1)
    Photographic portrait plate with wood border.
  - #44 Irene Dwen Pace [by Bruno Coloris?], 1949 (Box 1)
  - #45 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1949]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 1)
    Blake's work is a design after Kate Greenaway.
  - #46 Irene Dwen Pace, 1949; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 1)
  - #47 Irene Dwen Pace, 1949; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 1)
  - #48 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1949; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 1)
    Blake's work is a design after Vadasz.
  - #49 Irene Dwen Pace, 1949; Fleissig, Vitezslav (Box 2)
  - #50 Irene Dwen Pace, 1949; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 2)
    Blake's work is a design after Suzuki Harunobu.
  - #51 Irene Dwen Pace, 1949; Martini, Alberto, 1876-1954 (Box 2)
  - #52 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1949; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 2)
  - #53 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1949; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 2)
  - #54 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1949; Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828 (Box 2)
  - #55 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1949 1950; French, Harry Marvin (Box 2)
    With an additional landscape design by Alma and Harry French.
  - #56 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1950]; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 2)
  - #57 Irene Dwen Pace, 1950; Fleissig, Vitezslav (Box 2)
  - #58 Irene Dwen Pace, 1950; Fleissig, Vitezslav (Box 2)
  - #59 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1949; Kulhanek, Stanislav (Box 2)
  - #60 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1950; Ijserinkhuijsen, Frans J. (Box 2)
  - #61 Irene Dwen Pace, [1950] (Box 2)
  - #62 Irene Dwen Pace, [1950]; Gagliardo, Alberto Helios (Box 2)
  - #63 Irene & Ernst Pace, 1951; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 2)
  - #64 Irene Dwen Pace, 1950; Fleissig, Vitezslav (Box 2)
  - #65 Irene Dwen Pace, [1950]; McBrine, Ethel (Box 2)
  - #66 Irene Dwen Pace [by McBrine, Ethel?], [1950] (Box 2)
  - #67 Irene Dwen Pace [by McBrine, Ethel?], [1950] (Box 2)
  - #68 Irene Dwen Pace, [1950]; Prather, Lebert (Box 2)
  - #69 Irene Dwen Pace [by Prather, Lebert?], [1950] (Box 2)
  - #70 Irene D. Pace [by Prather, Lebert?], [1950] (Box 2)
  - #71-#73 Irene Dwen Andrews, I. D. A., Irene, [1940]; Gambini, Iorg (Box 2)
  - #71a I. D. A., [1940]; Gambini, Iorg (Box 2)
    Design includes a set of accordion-folded pen & ink monograms together with a floral colored woodblock print.
  - #74 Irene Dwen Pace, 1950; Bötel, Fritz (Box 2)
  - #75 Irene Pace, 1950; Bötel, Fritz (Box 2)
  - #76 Irene Dwen Pace, [1950]; Zwiers, Wim, 1922- (Box 2)
  - #77 Irene, 1950; Moss, Frances Dallam (Box 2)
  - #78 Irene Dwen Pace, 1951; Moss, Frances Dallam (Box 2)
  - #79 Ann Elizabeth Pace, [1951]; Wise, H. Owen (Box 2)
  - #80 E. Wyllys Andrews IV, [1951]; Wise, H. Owen (Box 2)
  - #81 Irene Pace, [1951]; Huchthausen, John (Box 2)
  - #82 Ernest Milton Pace Jr., [1951]; Young, Art (Box 2)
  - #83 Ernest Milton Pace Jr., [1951]; Young, Art (Box 2)
  - #84 Irene Pace, [1951]; Rome, Richardson, 1902- (Box 2)
  - #85 I. D. Pace, [1951]; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 2)
  - #87 Irene D. Pace, [1953]; Zetti, Italo, 1913-1978 (Box 2)
  - #88 Irene Dwen Pace, [1951]; Jong, Mar de (Box 2)
  - #89 Irene Pace, 1951; Rossell, Raimond (Box 2)
  - #90 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1951; Bötel, Fritz (Box 2)
  - #91 Irene D. Pace, 1951; Bötel, Fritz (Box 2)
  - #92 Irene and Ernest Pace, [1951]; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 2)
  - #93 Rear Admiral Ernest Milton Pace Jr., 1951; Holzer-Weinek, Irene (Box 2)
  - #94 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1951] (Box 2)
  - #95 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1951; Bötel, Fritz (Box 2)
  - #96 Irene Dwen Pace, [1951]; Wolff, Cor de (Box 2)
  - #97 Irene Pace, [1951]; Standish, Jason (Box 2)
  - #98 Irene D. Pace, [1951]; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 2)
  - #99 Irene Dwen Pace, [1951]; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 2)
  - #100 Irene Pace, [1951]; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 2)
  - #101 Irene Dwen Pace, [1952]; Holzer-Weinek, Irene (Box 2)
  - #102 Irene Dwen Pace, [1952] 1956; Holzer-Weinek, Irene (Box 3)
  - #103 Irene Dwen Pace, [1952]; Rapp, Cullen (Box 3)
  - #104, #104a Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1952]; Bötel, Fritz (Box 3)
  - #105 Irene Pace, 1952; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #106 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1952; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #107 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 3)
  - #108 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952; Zwiers, Wim, 1922- (Box 3)
  - #109 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952; Zwiers, Wim, 1922- (Box 3)
  - #110 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Zwiers, Wim, 1922- (Box 3)
  - #111 I. D. P., 1952; Beltran, V. (Box 3)
  - #112 Irene Pace, [1952]; Des Robert, Edmond (Box 3)
  - #113 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952-1955 1961; Voss, H. D. (Box 3)
  - #114 Irene Pace, 1953; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #115 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1953]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #116 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1953]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #117 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #118 Irene Pace, 1953; Kislinger, Max, 1895-1983 (Box 3)
  - #119 Irene Pace, [1953]; Šimon, Pavel (Box 3)
  - #120 Irene Pace, [1953]; Šimon, Pavel (Box 3)
  - #121 Irene Pace, [1953]; Kislinger, Max, 1895-1983 (Box 3)
  - #122 Irene Dwen Pace, [1953]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #123 Irene D. Pace, [1953]; Colin-Gury, P. (Box 3)
  - #124 Irene Dwen Pace, 1953-1959; Huber, Ernst, 1895-1960 (Box 3)
  - #125 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1953; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #126 The Paces, 1953 (Box 3)
  - #127 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952; Parmexano (Box 3)
  - #128 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952; Parmexano (Box 3)
  - #129 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1953]; Gagliardo, Alberto Helios (Box 3)
  - #130 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1953; Gagliardo, Alberto Helios (Box 3)
  - #131 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1953; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #132 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1953; Rossell, Raimond (Box 3)
  - #133 Irene Dwen Pace, 1953; Garcia Falgas, Luis (Box 3)
  - #134 Irene D. Pace, 1953; Marangoni, Tranquillo (Box 3)
  - #135 Irene Dwen Pace, 1953; Ballarate, G. (Box 3)
  - #136 Irene Dwen Pace, 1953-1954; Favet, Charles (Box 3)
  - #137 Irene Pace, [1954]; Florian, Michael, 1911- (Box 3)
  - #138 Irene Dwen Pace, 1952-1954; Huber, Ernst, 1895-1960 (Box 3)
  - #139 Ernest Milton Pace, [1954]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #140 Irene Dwen Pace, [1954]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #141 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1954; Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828 (Box 3)
  - #141 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Pringle, Will, 1914- (Box 3)
  - #143 Ernest Milton Pace Jr., 1954; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 3)
  - #144 Irene D. Pace, 1954; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 3)
  - #145 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985 (Box 3)
  - #146 Irene Pace, 1954; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985 (Box 3)
  - #147 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985 (Box 3)
  - #148 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Bird, Elisha Brown, 1867-1943 (Box 3)
  - #149 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Roth, Harry (Box 3)
  - #150 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1954; Simmons, L. E. (Box 3)
  - #151 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Jones, Dan Burne (Box 3)
  - #152 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1954]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 3)
  - #153 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1954; Coll, Alexandre (Box 3)
  - #154 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Huber, Ernst, 1895-1960 (Box 3)
  - #155 Ernest and Irene Pace, 1954; Rossell, Raimond (Box 4)
  - #156 Irene D. Pace, 1954 (Box 4)
  - #157 Irene D. Pace, 1954 (Box 4)
  - #158 Irene D. Pace, 1954; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 4)
  - #159-#162 Irene D. Pace, 1954; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971 (Box 4)
  - #163 Irene Dwen Pace, 1954; Favet, Charles (Box 4)
  - #164 Irene Pace, [1955]; Florian, Michael, 1911- (Box 4)
  - #165 Irene D. Pace, [1955]; Haffert, Hermann (Box 4)
  - #166 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955] 1957-1961; Haffert, Hermann (Box 4)
  - #167 Irene and Ernest Pace, [1955]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 4)
    Design after Utamara.
  - #168 Irene D. Pace, 1955; Wise, H. Owen (Box 4)
  - #169 Irene D. Pace, [1955]; Jones, Dan Burne (Box 4)
  - #170 Irene D. Pace, [1955]; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985 (Box 4)
  - #171 Irene Pace, [1955]; Favet, Charles (Box 4)
  - #172 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Favet, Charles (Box 4)
  - #173 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1955] (Box 4)
    Design is based on "an early English label."
  - #174 Irene D. Pace, 1955; Beltran, V. (Box 4)
  - #175 Irene and Ernest Pace, [1955]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 4)
  - #176 E. Milton Pace, 1955; Barton-Innes, C. J. (Box 4)
  - #177 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 4)
  - #178 Ernest and Irene Pace, 1955; Rossell, Raimond (Box 4)
  - #179 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 4)
  - #180 Irene and Ernest Pace [ by Tifft], [1955] (Box 4)
  - #181 Irene and Ernest Pace, [1955] (Box 4)
    Typographic label with photograph (snapshot at Zaca Lake).
  - #182 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Coll, Alexandre (Box 4)
  - #183 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Coll, Alexandre (Box 4)
  - #184 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Coll, Irene (Box 4)
  - #185 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Haefeli, Albert (Box 4)
    A fragment of Danse Macabre of St. Innocent's Cemetery. Engraved 1485 by Gyot Marchant.
  - #186 Irene Dwen Pace, 1955; Haefeli, Albert (Box 4)
  - #187 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 4)
  - #188 Irene Dwen Pace, [1955]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 4)
  - #189 Irene Dwen Pace, 1955; Junge, Carl S. (Carl Stephen), 1880-1972 (Box 4)
  - #190 Irene & Ernest Pace, 1955; Williamsburg Gazette Press (Box 4)
  - #191 Irene & Ernest Pace, 1955; Williamsburg Gazette Press (Box 4)
  - #192 Irene Dwen Pace, 1955-1957; Rossum, Ru van (Box 4)
  - #193-194 Irene D. Pace, [1956] (Box 4)
  - #195 Irene D. Pace, [1956] (Box 4)
  - #196 Irene Dwen Pace, 1955; Bötel, Fritz (Box 4)
  - #197 Irene Dwen Andrews, 1956; Feil, Otto, 1894-1985 (Box 4)
  - #198 Irene Dwen Pace, 1955; Feil, Otto, 1894-1985 (Box 4)
  - #199 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Feil, Otto, 1894-1985 (Box 4)
  - #200 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1956; Rossell, Raimond (Box 4)
  - #201 Irene Dwen Pace, 1944-1957; Briedé, Johan (Box 4)
  - #202 Ernest Milton Pace Jr., 1956; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 4)
  - #203 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 4)
  - #204 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Hemberger, Armin B., 1896-1974 (Box 4)
  - #205 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1956-1957; Beltran, V. (Box 4)
  - #206 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Feil, Otto, 1894-1985 (Box 4)
  - #207 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Feil, Otto, 1894-1985 (Box 4)
  - #208 Irene Pace, 1957; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 4)
  - #209 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 4)
  - #210 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 4)
  - #211 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 4)
  - #212 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 4)
  - #213 Irene Dwen Pace, 1956; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 4)
  - #214 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957] (Box 4)
  - #215 Irene Dwen Pace, 1957; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 5)
  - #216 Irene Dwen Pace, 1957; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 5)
  - #217 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Vannuccini, Enrico (Box 5)
  - #218 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #219 Irene Pace, 1957; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #220 Irene Pace, [1957]; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #221 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Voges, Elizabeth (Box 5)
  - #222 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1958; Rossell, Raimond (Box 5)
  - #223 Irene Pace, 1957; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973; Canul, E. (Box 5)
    Designed by Canul; engraved by Blake.
  - #224 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Gould, Juanita (Box 5)
  - #225 Irene Dwen Pace, [1957]; Gordon, Bank B. (Box 5)
  - #226 Irene Dwen Pace, [1958]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #227 Irene Dwen Pace, [1958]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #228 Irene Pace, [1958]; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #229 Irene Pace, [1958]; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #230 Irene Pace, [1958]; Hauke, Hans (Box 5)
  - #231 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #232 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #233 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #234 Irene Dwen Pace, [1958]; Zwiers, Wim, 1922- (Box 5)
  - #235 Irene and Ernest Pace, [1958]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #236 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #237 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #238 Irene Dwen Pace, 1957; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #239 Ernest Milton Pace, 1958; Ott, Norbert (Box 5)
    Artist age 15, son of Herbert Ott.
  - #240 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958-1961; Reitsma-Valença, Engelina (Engelien) (Box 5)
  - #241 Irene D. Pace, [1959] (Box 5)
  - #242 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959; Wolff, Cor de (Box 5)
  - #243 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959; Maekawa, Senpan (Box 5)
  - #244 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1959; Stuart, George (Box 5)
  - #245 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1959; Stuart, George (Box 5)
  - #246 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959; Kislinger, Max, 1895-1983 (Box 5)
  - #247 Irene D. Pace, [1959]; Maekawa, Senpan (Box 5)
  - #248 Rosemary Andrews, 1959; Stuart, George (Box 5)
  - #249 Irene Dwen Pace, 1958; Lorenzo, Alessandri (Box 5)
  - #250 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959; Lorenzo, Alessandri (Box 5)
  - #251 Irene D. Pace, 1959; Maekawa, Senpan (Box 5)
  - #252 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1959; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #253 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959-1961; Cox, R. (Box 5)
  - #254 Irene D. Pace, 1957-1959; Strik, Lou, 1921- (Box 5)
  - #255 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1959; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #256 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959-1960; Blake, Sara Eugenia, 1886-1973 (Box 5)
  - #257 Irene Dwen Pace, 1960; Kislinger, Max, 1895-1983 (Box 5)
  - #258 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959-1960; Kotrba, Emil (Box 5)
  - #259 Irene Dwen Pace, 1959-1960; Kotrba, Emil (Box 5)
  - #260 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1960; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #261 Irene Pace, 1960; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #262 Irene Pace, [1960]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #263 Irene D. Pace, 1960; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #264 Irene D. Pace, 1960; Ott, Herbert Stefan (Box 5)
  - #265 Irene Dwen Pace, [1960]; Ott, Norbert (Box 5)
  - #266 Irene Andrews Pace, 1960; Wille-Nielsen, Muggi (Box 5)
  - #267 Irene Andrews Pace, 1960; Wille-Nielsen, Muggi (Box 5)
  - #268 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1960; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #269 Irene D. Pace, [1960]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #270 Irene Dwen Pace, [1960]; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #271 Irene Dwen Pace, 1960; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #272 Irene Dwen Pace, 1960; Kotrba, Emil (Box 5)
  - #273 I. D. Pace, 1960; Beltran, V. (Box 5)
  - #274 Irene D. Pace, 1961; Broekstra, Th. (Box 5)
  - #275 Irene D. Pace, 1961; Nemoto, Kagai (Box 5)
  - #276 Irene and Ernest Pace, 1961; Fernández Saez, Julio, 1924- (Box 5)
  - #277 Irene Dwen Pace, 1961; Botella, J. V. (Box 5)
  - #278 Irene Dwen Pace, 1961; Cinybulk, Vojtěch, 1915- (Box 5)
  - #279 Irene Dwen Pace, 1961-1962; Cinybulk, Vojtěch, 1915- (Box 5)
  - #280 Irene Greene Dwen Pace, 1961; Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828 (Box 5)
    This design was printed from an original Bewick woodblock.
- Bookplates – Unmounted, Series II
  Series II is restricted.
  Arranged sequentially according to numbers assigned by Pace, which are roughly chronological by date of commission.
  - #2-#56 (incomplete) (Box 6)
  - #57-#69 (incomplete) (Box 7)
  - #70-#83 (Box 8)
  - #84-#95 (incomplete) (Box 9)
  - #96-#105 (Box 10)
  - #106-#117 (Box 11)
  - #118-#125 (Box 12)
  - #126-#134 (Box 13)
  - #135-#147 (Box 14)
  - #148-#166 (Box 15)
  - #167-#176 (Box 16)
  - #177-#185 (Box 17)
  - #186-#192 (Box 18)
  - #193-#203 (Box 19)
  - #204-#216 (Box 20)
  - #217-#227 (Box 21)
  - #228-#238 (Box 22)
  - #239-#251 (Box 23)
  - #252-#263 (Box 24)
  - #264-#278 (Box 25)
  - Andrews Bookplate Collection bookplates (Box 26)
- Process Materials, Series III
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series III is restricted and requires curatorial permission before use.
  This series contains examples of process materials—namely, blocks or plates—for many of Pace's personal bookplate designs. Whenever possible, Pace collected these materials directly from the artists, often as part of the initial negotiation for the commission.
  - #2-#17 (incomplete) (Box 27)
  - #19-#42 (incomplete) (Box 28)
  - #44-#77 (incomplete) (Box 29)
  - #78-#96 (incomplete) (Box 30)
  - #101-#118 (incomplete) (Box 31)
  - #121-#135 (incomplete) (Box 32)
  - #136-#158 (incomplete) (Box 33)
  - #163-#171 (incomplete) (Box 34)
  - #172-#203 (incomplete) (Box 35)
  - #204-#218 (incomplete) (Box 36)
  - #219-#231 (incomplete) (Box 37)
  - #232-#237 (Box 38)
  - #238-#242 (incomplete) (Box 39)
  - #243-#249 (incomplete) (Box 40)
  - #250-#261 (incomplete) (Box 41)
  - #262-#267 (Box 42)
  - #268-277 (incomplete) (Box 43)
  - 1 block (Box 44)
    The two unnumbered linocuts are designed for "A | Bibliotheca Irene Dwen Andrews" and "IDP | Bibliotheca Irene Dwen Pace." The unnumbered block is a design for "IGDA."
  - 3 engraved plates (Box 45)
    One plate is a design for the calling card of Dr. Edmund Andrews. Two additional plates are two different sizes of a portrait of Dr. Edmund Andrews.
- Correspondence and Ephemera, Series IV
  - Correspondence and Ephemera (Box 46)
    Series IV is restricted and requires curatorial permission before use.
    This folder contains correspondence and ephemera unattached to specific bookplates. It includes additional copies of the partial, type-written checklist of Pace's personal designs; four sets of draft correspondence together with bookplates selected by Pace for exchange; and various printed ephemera, including exchange cards explaining the various forms of Pace's name and also requesting that any bookplate correspondence be addressed to Mrs. Edmund Andrews.